<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Software Artist - aicte</title><link href="https://www.gowrishankarnath.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.gowrishankarnath.com/tag/aicte/feeds/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.gowrishankarnath.com/</id><updated>2019-09-11T12:05:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>My Throughts, My Learning</subtitle><entry><title>Tips for passing the courses offered by NPTEL</title><link href="https://www.gowrishankarnath.com/tips-for-passing-the-courses-offered-by-nptel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-11T13:05:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-09-11T12:05:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Gowrishankar S.</name></author><id>tag:www.gowrishankarnath.com,2019-05-11:/tips-for-passing-the-courses-offered-by-nptel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like to share a few tips for passing the courses offered by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; which are drawn from my own personal experience&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m happy to inform that I have passed the &lt;a href="https://nptel.ac.in/noc/E_Certificate/noc19-cs31/NPTEL19CS31S41160597191020551.jpg" target="_blank" style="color: rgb(6,69,173)"&gt;&lt;font color="#0066CC"&gt;Introduction to Internet of Things&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; course offered by &lt;a href="https://nptel.ac.in/" target="_blank" style="color: rgb(6,69,173)"&gt;&lt;font color="#0066CC"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with Elite + Gold&amp;nbsp;certification. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;font color = black&gt; &lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt;? &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; is an acronym for National Programme on Technology Enhanced Learning which is an initiative by seven Indian Institutes of Technology (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IIT&lt;/span&gt; Bombay, Delhi, Guwahati, Kanpur, Kharagpur, Madras and Roorkee) and Indian Institute of Science (IISc) for creating course contents in engineering and science. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; provides E-learning through online Web and Video courses in Engineering, Science and
humanities&amp;nbsp;streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course contents will be useful for training the faculty members and through them improve the quality of students. You can join/register &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; courses and access the materials for free. You have to pay a nominal amount only if you are registering for exams, leading to certification in your chosen course. Also, most of the institutions refund the amount that you have paid for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;certification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;font color = black&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Advantages of Earning Certification from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; courses are offered by premier institutions like IITs and&amp;nbsp;IISc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; certifications have become mandatory for promotions in most of the academic institutions and recruiters prefer students with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;certifications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few universities are also asking their students to take up and get certified as part of their course&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credits earned from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; courses are also recognized by most of the&amp;nbsp;universities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; Certifications are also approved and recognized as Faculty Development Programme (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FDP&lt;/span&gt;) by &lt;a href="https://nptel.ac.in/AICTE_FDP/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AICTE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; offers a scintillating opportunity to move our career forward and also to enhance our knowledge at our own pace and at less&amp;nbsp;cost.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are few tips to ace the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; courses drawn from my personal&amp;nbsp;experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than watching the videos, download the transcripts in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt; format. Personally, I feel it is easy to go through the&amp;nbsp;transcripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the printouts of all the PDFs beforehand itself. Do not wait for the arrival of the mail saying that video has been released for the particular week. You can find the PDFs of all the week at the beginning of the&amp;nbsp;course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to solve the assignments religiously. Remember that&amp;nbsp;for &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 week courses, only 3 best assignments are considered out of 4&amp;nbsp;assignments &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 week courses, only 6 best assignments are considered out of 8&amp;nbsp;assignments &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 week courses, only 8 best assignments are considered out of 12&amp;nbsp;assignments &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, you can miss few assignments but &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DO&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; if you are really serious about your course. Try to submit the assignments within deadline as there will not be any&amp;nbsp;extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; courses, assignment marks contribute 25% of the final score and exam marks contribute to 75% of the final score. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; Final Score = 25% of Assignment Marks + 75% of the Exam&amp;nbsp;Marks &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With good effort, you can easily crack most of the courses as the pass percentage is 40% (Assignment Marks + Exam&amp;nbsp;Marks). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By analyzing the assignments questions, you can gauge the kind of questions that will be asked in&amp;nbsp;exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; courses are part of a life long learning process. Prepare notes for each unit. You can always come back and refer these notes whenever&amp;nbsp;necessary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the courses have questions in Multiple Choice Questions (MCQs)&amp;nbsp;format. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming courses tend to be a little difficult in comparison to theoretical courses. You need to put a lot of effort into understanding the basics of programming&amp;nbsp;concepts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPTEL&lt;/span&gt; allocates exam centers at different locations rather than nearer to the residential/office address that you had provided while registering for your exam. Plan and Schedule your travel&amp;nbsp;appropriately. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revise your course notes the previous day of your exam and get good&amp;nbsp;sleep. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not forget to drink lots of&amp;nbsp;water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I say is, take the course that is of interest to you, put effort and hope for&amp;nbsp;good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good&amp;nbsp;Luck!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="nptel"></category><category term="certification"></category><category term="aicte"></category><category term="swayam"></category><category term="iot"></category></entry></feed>