<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Software Artist - Coding-Gems</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/tag/coding-gems/feeds/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-01-10T23:58:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>My Throughts, My Learning</subtitle><entry><title>Copy the Contents of Multiple Files into Single File or Merge Multiple Files into Single File</title><link href="/copy-the-contents-of-multiple-files-into-single-file-or-merge-multiple-files-into-single-file.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-09T16:23:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-01-10T23:58:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Gowrishankar S.</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-12-09:/copy-the-contents-of-multiple-files-into-single-file-or-merge-multiple-files-into-single-file.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This article is about copying the contents of multiple files into single file or to merge multiple files into single&amp;nbsp;file.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Problem:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was facing a situation wherein I had hundreds of files lying around and had to take printout of all the files. Having to take printout of each and every file proved to be&amp;nbsp;nightmare.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution was to merge all the files into a single file or copy the contents of multiple files into single&amp;nbsp;file.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before issuing these commands at the command prompt change to the directory where all the files are present. The code shown below copies the contents from all the files ending with &lt;em&gt;.py&lt;/em&gt; extension into a new file called &lt;em&gt;mergedFile.doc&lt;/em&gt;. The reason I created a word doc file is, it’ll be easier to take printout and had no reason to think&amp;nbsp;otherwise.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;copy /b *.py mergedFile.doc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To merge multiple text files into a single document file the command used is given&amp;nbsp;below.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;copy /b *.txt mergedFile.doc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To merge multiple text files into a single text file the command used is given&amp;nbsp;below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;copy /b *.txt mergedFile.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To merge multiple java files into a single document file the command used is given&amp;nbsp;below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;copy /b *.java mergedFile.doc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code shown here is tested on Windows 7/8/10&amp;nbsp;machine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Coding-Gems"></category></entry></feed>